Cultural Survival Records MS180
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Ted Macdonald Cultural Survival records, 1976 -- 1996; MS180.001; 24.0 Linear Feet
  - Cultural Survival projects, 1978 -- 1993; MS180.001.001
    - Peru: COICA Environmentalist Alliance Coordinating Committee, 1991; MS180.001.012.00010 (Box 12)
      Coordinadora de las Organizaciones Indi_genas de la Cuenca Amazo_nica, or the Coordinating Body of Indigenous Organizations of the Amazon Basin (COICA). Trip report from the second meeting of the COICA- Environmentalist Alliance Coordinating Committee. Meeting's objective was to outline a work plan for indigenous land claims.
    - Peru: COICA meeting Iquitos, 1990; MS180.001.012.00011 (Box 12)
      Coordinadora de las Organizaciones Indi_genas de la Cuenca Amazo_nica, or the Coordinating Body of Indigenous Organizations of the Amazon Basin (COICA). Correspondence from the Iquitos Summit between Indian leaders and environmentalists. Includes the Iquitos Declaration and some newspaper articles in relation to the Summit.
    - Peru: COICA trip to Washington, 1989; MS180.001.012.00012 (Box 12)
      Coordinadora de las Organizaciones Indi_genas de la Cuenca Amazo_nica, or the Coordinating Body of Indigenous Organizations of the Amazon Basin (COICA). Includes project proposal request and COICA meeting roster.
    - Peru: COICA "Grupo Coordinadora" Amazon, 1984 -- 1990; MS180.001.012.00013 (Box 12)
      Coordinadora de las Organizaciones Indi_genas de la Cuenca Amazo_nica, or the Coordinating Body of Indigenous Organizations of the Amazon Basin (COICA). Correspondence, agreement, financial and narrative reports on grant coming from Oxfam-America.
      COICA (Organization); Oxfam America
    - Peru: II Congress concerns, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.001.012.00014 (Box 12)
      Chronology of correspondence between Cultural Survival, COICA, and others about the II Indigenous Congress held in Bolivia, Dec. 2-7 1992. Includes a trip report. Coordinadora de las Organizaciones Indi_genas de la Cuenca Amazo_nica, or the Coordinating Body of Indigenous Organizations of the Amazon Basin (COICA).
    - Peru: Consejo Aguaruna Huambisa, 1987 -- 1990; MS180.001.012.00015 (Box 12)
      Aguaruna and Huambisa Council (Consejo Aguaruna y Huambisa) assesses production of cacao as a cash crop. Focus on family agricultural production.
      Anthropology Resource Center (Washington, D.C.)
    - Peru: Consejo Indio de Sud America, 1980 -- 1986; MS180.001.012.00016 (Box 12)
      Correspondence, notes, and presentation reports on the Indican Council of South America.
      Consejo Indio de Sudame_rica
    - Peru: COPAL, 1979 -- 1986; MS180.001.012.00017 (Box 12)
      COPAL: Solidaridad con los Grupos Nativos. Brochure on tribal survival in the Amazon. Newsletters and newspaper articles on the infringement of Campa property rights and the plans of the Peruvian government to build roads. Focus on the native Campa people. Includes financials and correspondence.
    - Peru: Ene Campa/Beauclerk, 1983 -- 1984; MS180.001.012.00018 (Box 12)
      Project proposal for bilingual teaching aids in basic agriculture for Peruvian Forest Communities.
    - Peru: Fundacion Peruana Conservacion de la Naturaleza (FPCN), 1987 -- 1991; MS180.001.012.00019 (Box 12)
      Financials, correspondence, and project proposal for Fundacion Peruana para la Conservacion de la Naturaleza (FPCN).
      Fundacio_n Peruana para la Conservacio_n de la Naturaleza
    - Peru: IV film festival, 1991; MS180.001.012.00020 (Box 12)
      Project summary for the American Film Festival of Indigenous Peoples
    - Peru: ORACH Achual land demarcation, 1981 -- 1982; MS180.001.012.00021 (Box 12)
      Organización Achuar Chayat (ORACH). Report on legal land titling, including maps. Focus on Achuar land demarcations.
    - Peru: Central Selva Resource Management Project, 1981 -- 1984; MS180.001.012.00022 (Box 12)
      Contracts, correspondence, anticipated work schedules, analysis of planned agricultural development, description of duties, and project proposals for the Central Selva Resource Management Project in the Palcazu Valley.
    - Peru: Palcazu project, 1981 -- 1983; MS180.001.012.00023 (Box 12)
      Presentation notes and report on native communities and colonization in the Palcazu Valley. The Palcazu project focuses on forest management and native Amuesha communities. Includes correspondence.
    - Peru: Informe Final: Especialista en Manejo de Bosques Naturales Centro Científico Tropical TSC-107-C, 1986; MS180.001.012.00024 (Box MS180 Shared 1)
      Spanish-language final report of Peru project with pictures.
    - Peru: Peru Mujer, 1986; MS180.001.013.00001 (Box 13)
      Peru Mujer is a non-profit organization meant to encourage the participation of women in development through study and action. The institution has been legally recognized in Peru since March 8, 1979. Includes correspondence and brochures about the organization.
    - Peru: Sendero Luminoso, 1984; MS180.001.013.00002 (Box 13)
      Photocopies of newspaper articles.
    - Peru: URIARTE Achuar land demarcation Part 1 of 2, 1980 -- 1985; MS180.001.013.00003 (Box 13)
      Correspondence and project summaries for Achuar land titles.
    - Peru: URIARTE Achuar land demarcation Part 2 of 2, 1980 -- 1985; MS180.001.013.00004 (Box 13)
    - Peru: US AID, 1981 -- 1983; MS180.001.013.00005 (Box 13)
      Notes and correspondence on U.S. AID's efforts to desgin a sustained-yield development program for the Palcazu Valley.
    - Peru: Biosphere reserves Yanachaca, 1984; MS180.001.013.00006 (Box 13)
      Article from CS Quarterly on people, parks, and petroleum in Peru.
    - Phillippines: Lumad People's Alliance for Land and Self-Determination, 1986; MS180.001.013.00007 (Box 13)
      Letter proposal for the launching of the first Lumad Alliance. Theme is for Lumads to elect their own representatives, share local situations affecting the Lumads, and create an understanding of self-determination.
    - Siberia: CS field programs, 1993; MS180.001.013.00008 (Box 13)
      Project proposal on developing sustainable resource uses which protect the indigenous Udege culture. Includes brochures on the Siberan Forests Protection Project.
    - US: International Labor Organization, 1988 -- 1989; MS180.001.013.00009 (Box 13)
      The International Labour Organization (ILO) was founded in 1919 and is the only tripartite U.N. agency with government, employer, and worker representatives. The governments and the social partners of the economy can debate labor standards and policies. Information on the United Nations working group on indigenous populations and its role in the advancement of their rights. Includes revisions of international labour organization convention on indigenous and tribal populations.
      International Labour Organization.
    - US: International Labor Organization Coordination, 1988; MS180.001.013.00010 (Box 13)
    - US: International Labor Organization mailing list, 1988; MS180.001.013.00011 (Box 13)
      Mailing list of South American support organizations.
    - US: ITTO, 1991; MS180.001.013.00012 (Box 13)
      Discussion papers and grant proposals from the International Tropical Timber Organization (ITTO). ITTO was established by the United Nations in 1986. It promotes conservation and sustainable management, use and trade of tropical forest resources.
    - US: IUCN John Cordell, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.001.013.00013 (Box 13)
      Faxes sent to John Cordell at IUCN-The World Conservation Union.
      IUCN--The World Conservation Union
    - Venezuela: People and protected areas workshop Caracas, 1992; MS180.001.013.00014 (Box 13)
      Panel for IV World Congress on National Parks and Protected Areas.
    - Venezuela: IUCN Part 1of 2, 1990; MS180.001.013.00015 (Box 13)
      Draft programme for the IV World Congress on National Parks and Protected Areas. Includes Congress recommendations.
    - Venezuela: IUCN Part 2 of 2, 1992; MS180.001.013.00016 (Box 13)
      Official programme for the IV World Congress on National Parks and Protected Areas. Includes book on guidelines for establishing marine protected areas. Includes draft recommendations.
    - US: Peace research Bill Ury, 1988; MS180.001.013.00017 (Box 13)
      Draft written by Ury on war and peace among hunters and gatherers.
    - US: Board of Directors James Anaya, 1992 -- 1993; MS180.001.013.00018 (Box 13)
      Cultural Survival Board of Directors' resumes. Journal article written by Anaya titled, "Indigenous Rights Norms in Contemporary International Law."
  - Cultural Survival special projects, 1983 -- 1992; MS180.001.002
    - Haiti: Cultural development program, 1987; MS180.001.013.00019 (Box 13)
      The Haitian Cultural Development Project has an objective of sustaining national culture and improving international understanding of Haitian culture. Includes letter of agreement, correspondence, and background.
    - India: Tibet Project Smith, Warren, 1990 -- 1992; MS180.001.013.00020 (Box 13)
      The Tibetan Oral History Project focuses on helping Tibetan children practice English through learning more about their own culture. Includes correspondence.
    - Mexico: Special Projects, 1992; MS180.001.013.00021 (Box 13)
      Letter of agreement, amendments, approval memo, correspondence, financial reports, and background info on the Kekchi High School Scholarship Fund (KHSF). KHSF provides scholarship money for Kekchi children to go to college. Folder also includes information on Xicaque donations.
    - Mexico: Na Bolom's Reforestation Program, 1987; MS180.001.013.00022 (Box 13)
      Project to expand existing reforestation program throughout the Chiapas highlands. Includes creation of local community tree nurseries and tree-planting programs.
    - Mexico: Chiapas Culture Center, Walter Morris, 1984; MS180.001.013.00023 (Box 13)
      Sna is "the house" and Jolobil means "tissue" in Tzotzil Maya. It is a non-profit Indian organization founded in 1976 with the objective of revitalizing traditional techniques of Maya textile art and marketing of handicrafts; this serves as a source of income for weavers and their families living in the highlands of Chiapas. Includes descriptions of the project.
    - Mexico: Resource management, Chip Morris, 1989 -- 1992; MS180.001.014.00001 (Box 14)
      A proposal for a network of Maya storefront museums and proposals for more artisan development programs.
    - Mexico: Sna Jolobil, 1985 -- 1988; MS180.001.014.00002 (Box 14)
      Sna Jolobil business cards. Letters and articles written on the Sna Jolobil Weavers' Cooperative in Chiapas. Includes book A Millenium of Weaving in Chiapas, which has color illustrations. Also includes a calendar and postcards produced by the Sna Jolobil Weavers' Cooperative and an evaluation of the special project.
    - Mexico: Sna Jolobil, Weavers Cooperative, 1984 -- 1987; MS180.001.014.00003 (Box 14)
      The project "Living Maya Arts" was established to promote traditional art within Chiapas. Support went to Sna Jolobil, a weaving cooperative, and was coordinated by Walter F. Morris. Folder includes project summary, correspondence, payments, financial and narrative reports, and background information. Includes photographs of female Maya weavers.
    - Namibia: Marshall, 1983 -- 1988; MS180.001.014.00004 (Box 14)
      Project reports submitted by the Ju/Wa Bushman Development Foundation in Windhoek, Namibia. Report focuses on activities, funding, project components, and issues. Includes maps, hand-written notes, correspondence, and a preliminary report on changes in the economic life of the !Kung (Ju/wasi) people of Bushman land.
    - US: Indian Law Resource Center, 1991; MS180.001.014.00005 (Box 14)
      Fax submitted by Ted Macdonald about Indian Law Resource Center.
  - Cultural Survival files, 1976 -- 1994; MS180.001.003
    - Cultural Survival summary of activities, core support, 1984; MS180.001.014.00006 (Box 14)
      Chronological summary of activities filed at the beginning of this group to assist in understanding CS activities.
    - AID/Bolivia, 1992; MS180.001.014.00007 (Box 14)
      Copy of the Instituto para el Desarrollo Sostenible de la Amazonía's general projects document.
    - America's Watch/ Cauca, 1987; MS180.001.014.00008 (Box 14)
      Letter from Ted Macdonald on human rights situation of the Indians in Cauca.
    - Anniversary organization CS 20th anniversary, statements, 1992; MS180.001.014.00009 (Box 14)
      Anniversary statements made by various organizations working with Cultural Survival.
    - Anthropology Resource Center, 1977 -- 1988; MS180.001.014.00010 (Box 14)
      Working papers and background documents on various anthropological studys.
    - Arthur D. Little proposal for La Planada workshop, 1990; MS180.001.014.00011 (Box 14)
      Correspondence on proposal for funding from the Arthur D. Little Foundation.
      Arthur D. Little Foundation
    - Articles distributed, 1992; MS180.001.014.00012 (Box 14)
      Published magazine and journal articles relevant to Cultural Survival's interests.
    - Article "Indigenous People/Conservation/Sustainable Development" -Peter Poole, 1988; MS180.001.014.00013 (Box 14)
    - Ashoka, 1990; MS180.001.014.00014 (Box 14)
      Ashoka: Innovators For The Public is an international foundation that offers grants to those working in an area of special concern.
      Ashoka Innovators for the Public (Organization)
    - Budget, 1983 -- 1986; MS180.001.014.00015 (Box 14)
    - Conference land/resource rights in Amazonia, 1991; MS180.001.014.00016 (Box 14)
      Amazonian land seminars.
    - CCS workshop final paper: working with Indian people in L.A. and workshop summary, 1991; MS180.001.014.00017 (Box 14)
      The role of NGOs working with Indian federations in Central and South America workshop summary.
    - Workshop-CCS, 1991; MS180.001.014.00018 (Box 14)
      Correspondence on a workshop hosted by the Cultural Survival Center titled, "The Role of NGOs Working with Indian Federations."
    - CCS workshop logistics, 1991; MS180.001.014.00019 (Box 14)
      Head counts, planning meeting summaries and reports, budget reports, conference drafts, and correspondence on the logistics for the meeting with NGOs.
    - CCS workshop, 1991; MS180.001.014.00020 (Box 14)
      Proposal to the Rockefeller Foundation. Includes purchase orders, correspondence, and contact information for conference participants.
    - CCS workshop notes from conference, 1991; MS180.001.014.00021 (Box 14)
      Handwritten notes taken at the conference and a list of participating organizations in the conference, "The Role of NGOs Working with Indian Federations."
    - CCS seminar, 1991; MS180.001.014.00022 (Box 14)
      Papers from the members of the Governing Board of the Institute of Indigenous People.
    - Center for Cultural Survival, 1990 -- 1992; MS180.001.014.00023 (Box 14)
      A list of organizations in the Cultural Survival databass, drafts of employment policies and benefits, and notes on proposed seminars.
    - Central America program correspondence, 1990 -- 1993; MS180.001.014.00024 (Box 14)
      Central America program proposed budget, project proposals, and correspondence.
    - Central American program: Mac Chapin, Leslie McNertney, Tony Stocks, 1988 -- 1989; MS180.001.014.00025 (Box 14)
      Reports on ethnic minorities in El Salvador and Belize.
    - Central America program final report for USAID grant no. LAC-0003-G-SS-7045-00, 1991; MS180.001.014.00026 (Box 14)
      Final report for grant titled, "Strengthening Democratic Institutions Among Indian Peoples of Central America."
      United States. Agency for International Development.
    - Project Chambira, 1990; MS180.001.014.00027 (Box 14)
      Project focused on sewing workshop.
    - Central America program description, 1990; MS180.001.015.00001 (Box 15)
      Programs descriptions of CS printed in both English and Spanish.
    - Children's letter sent to CS, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.001.015.00002 (Box 15)
      Letters sent to Cultural Survival, mostly from younger students and school groups.
    - CIKARD, 1989; MS180.001.015.00003 (Box 15)
      Newsletter from the Center for Indigenous Knowledge for Agriculture and Rural Development (CIKARD).
      Iowa State University. Center for Indigenous Knowledge for Agriculture and Rural Development
    - Colegio Verde/Margarita Marino de Botero, 1988; MS180.001.015.00004 (Box 15)
      Letter about reimbursement for travel expenses.
    - Colombia trip report, 1988; MS180.001.015.00005 (Box 15)
      Colombia trip report submitted by William R. Burch, Jr.
    - Computers: Apple proposal, 1992 -- 1993; MS180.001.015.00006 (Box 15)
      A proposal to Apple Computers for a special project in support of the Indigenous Rights Project. Includes correspondence.
    - BSO/Origin, 1992; MS180.001.015.00007 (Box 15)
      Correspondence with Origin and the discussion process for developing a center database with BSO.
    - Computers:BSO, 1992; MS180.001.015.00008 (Box 15)
      Correspondence on working with BSO/Origin to create a database.
    - Computers: email, 1993; MS180.001.015.00009 (Box 15)
      Correspondence on setting up computer connections. Includes a floppy disc.
    - Computers: networks, 1993; MS180.001.015.00010 (Box 15)
      Correspondence on plans for CS computers and networks.
    - Computers: database, 1992; MS180.001.015.00011 (Box 15)
      Specification and project outline for the peoples' base, a computer database for Cultural Survival.
    - Computers: the peoples base, 1992; MS180.001.015.00012 (Box 15)
      Management summary for a database that would hold records on indigenous peoples and the organizations involved with indigenous peoples.
    - CONFENIAE: correspondence, 1985; MS180.001.015.00013 (Box 15)
      Travel grants to Washington, D.C. for a folk festival and correspondence with Confederacio_n de Nacionalidades Indi_genas de la Amazoni_a Ecuatoriana (CONFENIAE).
    - Congress of Americanist, 1991; MS180.001.015.00014 (Box 15)
      Information, including topics presented, at the 47th International Congress of Americanists.
    - Conservation, Food & Health Foundation, 1992; MS180.001.015.00015 (Box 15)
      Correspondence with the Conservation, Food & Health Foundation. The foundation supports the conservation of natural resources.
      Conservation, Food and Health Foundation, Inc.
    - Conservationists "Debt for Nature" rainforest bill, 1987 -- 1988; MS180.001.015.00016 (Box 15)
      Articles on third world debt and natural resources conservation.
    - CSQ articles on biosphere reserves in Central America, 1985 -- 1989; MS180.001.015.00017 (Box 15)
    - Databases paradox: all, 1992; MS180.001.015.00018 (Box 15)
      Directory of database drives.
    - Databases paradox: contacts, 1993; MS180.001.015.00019 (Box 15)
      Database contacts.
    - Databases paradox: CSE, 1993; MS180.001.015.00020 (Box 15)
      Database standard reports.
    - Databases paradox: donors, 1993; MS180.001.015.00021 (Box 15)
      List of donor names stored in database.
    - Databases paradox: foundations, 1991 -- 1993; MS180.001.015.00022 (Box 15)
      Foundation updates on current funding and a list of foundation names stored in database.
    - Databases paradox: outreach, 1992 -- 1993; MS180.001.015.00023 (Box 15)
      Standard reports on organizations listed in the database and outreach.
    - Databases paradox: press, 1993; MS180.001.015.00024 (Box 15)
      Letter about press list in Paradox database.
    - House of Reps. Cultural Survival Act, 1989 -- 1991; MS180.001.015.00025 (Box 15)
      Congressional proceedings and faxed correspondence on the Cultural Survival Act, a bill to assist indigenous peoples in Central and South America. The bill focuses on helping protect land and cultures as well as assisting indigenous peoples take roles in their nations' democratic institutions.
    - Declarations, 1976 -- 1992; MS180.001.015.00026 (Box 15)
      Declaration on the Rights of Indigenous Peoples, Forest Peoples Charter, Convention on the Protection of Archaeological, Historical & Artistic Heritage of the Americas, codes of conduct, Declaration of Belem, and economic botany guidelines.
    - Dev. Foundations, 1992 -- 1993; MS180.001.015.00027 (Box 15)
      Sources of funds and organizational budget.
    - Dev. Exit memo, 1993; MS180.001.015.00028 (Box 15)
      Memo on unresolved membership issues.
    - Dev. Donors campaign, 1993; MS180.001.015.00029 (Box 15)
      Fundraiser lists and revised fundraising plans.
    - Dev. Foundations CSE, 1993; MS180.001.015.00030 (Box 15)
      Proposal for a rainforest marketing project and priorities summary for CSE overall.
    - Development updates, 1990 -- 1992; MS180.001.015.00031 (Box 15)
      Development updates on fundraising activities.
    - Dev. Foundations Fundacion Capacitar, 1993; MS180.001.015.00032 (Box 15)
      Draft proposal to Fundacion Capacitar for professional collaboration on training and research programs between Ecuadorian institutions and Cultural Survival.
    - Dev. Foundations GIS, 1992; MS180.001.015.00033 (Box 15)
      Introduction to gap analysis, a geographic information system used to map species and vegetation as biodiversity indicators.
    - Dev. Foundations women, 1992; MS180.001.015.00034 (Box 15)
      Report on gender initiative at Cultural Survival.
    - Dev. Foundations reassuring reporting, 1991 -- 1993; MS180.001.015.00035 (Box 15)
      A proposal to the John Merck Fund and narrative summaries of the budget for core Cultural Survival expenses from a grant from the Ford Foundation.
      Ford Foundation; John Merck Fund
    - Dev. Foundations update, 1993; MS180.001.015.00036 (Box 15)
      Memos on cash flow summaries.
    - Dev. Grant proposals Pumaren: homeland, 1993; MS180.001.015.00037 (Box 15)
      Correspondence regarding Cultural Survival's submitted proposal to the Homeland Foundation to support the PUMAREN Community Forestry Project. PUMAREN is an Indian-directed resource management program in Napo province of the Ecuadorian Amazon.
    - Dev. Info, 1992; MS180.001.015.00038 (Box 15)
      Development info on fundraising and grant guides.
    - Distribution sheets, 1992; MS180.001.015.00039 (Box 15)
      Staff circulation sheets.
    - Ecuador/proposal- Cooperativa de Desarrollo de la Comunidad "Imbaburapac Churimi Canchic", 1987; MS180.001.015.00040 (Box 15)
    - Ecuador INCRAE, 1982; MS180.001.015.00041 (Box 15)
      Paper titles, "Los Indigenas Amazonicos Permanecen en la Obscuridad."
    - Ecuador Intermisional Council for Coordination of Amazonian Region, 1982; MS180.001.015.00042 (Box 15)
      Declarations by the council written in Spanish.
    - Ecuador Limoncocha, 1982; MS180.001.015.00043 (Box 15)
      A report on the current health status in Limoncocha, written in Spanish.
    - Ecuador Programa de Antropologica para el Ecuador, 1977; MS180.001.015.00044 (Box 15)
      Notes on an anthropological program for Ecuador, including an ethnicity map.
    - Environmental Organizations, 1989 -- 1992; MS180.001.015.00045 (Box 15)
      Brochures and correspondence on intensive English programs, Tierra Viva, reindeer surveys on the Belcher Islands, and Wings for the Earth.
    - Indigenous residents as resource managers, 1988 -- 1991; MS180.001.015.00046 (Box 15)
      Report on indigenous residents as resource managers program and a proposal for forest residents as forest managers.
    - General correspondence (Esther/Celina/Ted), 1989 -- 1993; MS180.001.015.00047 (Box 15)
      Curriculum vitae for Norman Chapin, correspondence from Ted Macdonald, Esther's general correspondence with Jeff Knaebel on Gwich'in Niintsyaa (a resolution to prohibit development in the calving grounds of the Porcupine caribou herd), and Esther and Celina correspondence.